

PERSONAL CONTACTS

- Adress: 60 rue du Dr. Bauer,
 93400, Saint Ouen, France
- bicchiericristiano@gmail.com
- Mobile: +39 3387<u>581</u>170
- Online portfolio: zioCristia.github.io
- GitHub: github.com/zioCristia

PERSONAL PROFILE

My education as well as my multinational experience have allowed me to develop a great spirit of collaboration, curiosity and a desire to get involved.

I am addicted to face new challenges and find solutions to them. I would like to put my programming skills as well as my

PROGRAMMING LANGAUGES

creativity to your profit.

- ••• C, C++, Python, Java
- •••• HTML, CSS

TECHNOLOGIES

- •••• MySQL, Git, Jira, Eclipse
- •••• Postman, AspectJ

LANGUAGES

- Italian: mother tongue
- English: C1, TOEIC 965/990
- French: fluent

HOBBIES

- Reading, movies, tennis
- Cycling: I did the tour of Brittany in six days for 600km

CRISTIANO BICCHIERI

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Backend developer engineering

DPS - Digital Product Simulation | Mars 2022 - present

- Backend development of a collaborative engineering web application
- Use of Java 8 with Hibernate, AspectJ, Rest API, MySQL
- Bug fixing and feature development
- Use of Jira and GitLab

Mechatronic engineer - semester 8, curricular activity

Capax Infinity | April - June 2021

- Creation of a Python program for the optimisation of the components of a multicopter and flight time hypothesis
- Worked in a team of 3 people using Colaboratory

Mechatronic engineer - semester 7, curricular activity

ISAE-Supmeca | October 2020 - January 2021

- Creation of a software to perform autonomous surface inspections with a 6-axis UR10 robot from Universal Robots.
- Use of Python inside Spyder

PROJECTS

Creation of a server to automate IoT Devices

Link GitHub: https://github.com/zioCristia/energy-saver-ha-automations Installation of a Linux server on an Intel NUC to manage home IoT devices via Home Assistant installed via Docker.

• 3D Java Renderer

Link GitHub: https://github.com/zioCristia/3DJavaRenderer A simple 3D Java Renderer created to simulate the 3D space dispositions of packages inside a truck. Capability of changing the view with the mouse.

FORMATION

ISAE-Supmeca

Mechatronics Engineer, MSc | Oct 2020 - present

Erasmus Double Degree Project with the Polytechnic of Turin

Turin Polytechnic

Aerospace Engineer, MSc | Sept 2019 - present

Mechanical and fluidodynamic design engineering

Aerospace engineer, BSc | Sept 2016 - Oct 2019

Thesis in "Calculation of the lift distribution of swept wings" through the design of a Matlab program.